NICOLE FORMENTI

Belfast, BT5 4QL - 07578919977

n.formentipedroia@outlook.com

LinkedIn Profile
GitHub Profile

Trustworthy front-end web developer in the making, with dedicated work ethic and ready for a new challenge. I have a strong passion for web development, and I recently graduated from the Bath Spa University Web Development Bootcamp, which involved creating dynamic and user-friendly websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. This new path in web development is the natural consequence of the problem-solving oriented mindset that I have applied in all my previous work experiences.

I am self-motivated to consistently provide first-class results against stringent targets and deadlines and overachieve goals.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

CURRENT

FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT COURSE, UNIVERSITY OF HELSINKI

Learning Outcomes:

• React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, GraphQL and TypeScript

CURRENT

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT LIBRARIES, FREE CODE CAMP

Learning Outcomes:

• Bootstrap, jQuery, Saas, React, Redux

AUGUST 2023

WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP, BATH SPA UNIVERSITY

A LIST OF ALL THE PROJECTS WE HAVE WORKED ON IS AVAILABLE ON MY GITHUB PROFILE

Learning Outcomes Achieved:

- How to build responsive and interactive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React
- How to use third-party APIs to build complete applications

2011 - 2018

MASTER OF ARTS AND BACHELOR OF ARTS IN ITALIAN LINGUISTICS, UNIVERSITY

OF BERN, SWITZERLAND

Magna cum laude degree.

2010 - 2011

CAMBRIDGE FIRST CERTIFICATE, ESL SAN DIEGO, CALIFORNIA, USA **GOETHE ZERTIFIKAT B2,** PROLOG BERLIN, BERLIN, GERMANY

JUNE 2010

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, LOCARNO, SWITZERLAND

High school diploma (Business&Law).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2020 - CURRENT

FOUNDER/CEO, SKINDNESS

- Managed Skindness' brick-and-mortar store from October 2020 to March 2022, selecting the brands
 we work with and making sure targets are hit. I conducted target market research to scope out the
 industry competition and identify advantageous trends.
- Secured sufficient funds to cover business obligations by tracking expenses and budgeting accurately.
- Managed the transition from brick-and-mortar store to online shop by creating and maintaining Skindness' website, constantly improving SEO and functionality of the channel.
- Managed the business' marketing campaigns through social media and SEO, while constantly analysing industry trends and tracking competitors' activities.

MAY 2020 - JULY 2020

MICROSOFT SALES COACH AND TEAM LEADER, CONCENTRIX

- Improved my team's performances through consistent training and coaching while maintaining a problem-solving mindset. Assessed training program effectiveness on regular basis and achieved top performance by adapting to a rapidly changing, competitive environment.
- Responsibly managed my team's offline time to ensure consistent meeting of SLA target
- Delivered targets and KPIs for consistent performance progress, while monitoring multiple databases and analysis tools to ensure KPIs were met.

MAY 2019 - APRIL 2020

MICROSOFT SALES SPECIALIST, CONCENTRIX

- Managed communications for both the Italian and the UK market, providing first-rate service to all
 customers and potential customers while generating leads and opportunities.
- Showcased product features to customers and discussed technical details to overcome objections and lock in sales.
- Consistently met targets and achieved top performances monthly.
- Helped the coaching team achieve better results by monitoring the quality of the interactions between sale specialists and prospective customers.

OCTOBER 2018 - APRIL 2019

VF CUSTOMER CARE SPECIALIST, CONCENTRIX

- Managed communications for both the French and the Italian Market with a positive attitude and a focus on customer satisfaction and problem solving.
- Managed the smooth operation of refunds, warranty cases, shipment, ... through tools like Magento, Salesforce, Sales Centre, Ingenico and WorldPay.
- Resolved concerns with products or services to help with retention and drive sales.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Visual Studio Code, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- External APIs
- GitHub
- Figma

SOFT SKILLS

- Fluency in Italian, English, French and German
- Problem-solving mindset

- WordPress, Shopify
- Magento, Salesforce
- Microsoft 365 Suite, Dynamics 365, Microsoft Azure
- Extensive commercial experience (sales, client relationship management, office administration)
- Stakeholder management, external as well as internal
- Time management and prioritization